JASON JACOBS



SUMMARY

Jason is a graduate of a BSc Computer Science program at the University of Guyana and a driven individual who has built experience in working within System Administration, Cybersecurity and Web Development along the lines of Web Application Security Assessment, the use of Security Information and Event Management Systems while also developing small to medium scale applications using HTML, CSS, PHP, and the Amazon Web Services platform.



EDUCATION

Caribbean Certificate of Examinations | Richard Ishmael Secondary SEPTEMBER 2012 – JULY 2017

English A - Grade 2, Mathematics - Grade 3, Information Technology - Grade 2, Principles of Business - Grade 2, Social Studies - Grade 3, Economics - Grade 3, Office Administration - Grade 3, Principles of Accounts - Grade 3

BSc. Computer Science | University of GuyanaSEPTEMBER 2017 – JULY 2021

- Contributed to the service of arranging cyber awareness materials as an Events Co-Ordinator in the University's Cybersecurity Club in the academic year 2017/2018.
- Completed a final-year project in Machine Learning that detects negative review spam that unreasonably demotes mobile applications.
- Created a Social Media platform for Applied Project using PHP, MySQL, and AJAX that provides group features, friends, and private messaging similar to the Facebook platform.
- Graduated from the degree program with a Pass.



EXPERIENCE

Cybersecurity Consultant | The G5 Cybersecurity Foundation Ltd. FEBRUARY 2023 – PRESENT

- Conducted penetration testing and vulnerability assessments of systems to identify and mitigate potential security threats, ensuring the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of sensitive information.
- Conducted comprehensive cybersecurity risk assessments, utilizing enterprise-level and open-source tools to identify and prioritize vulnerabilities and threats, and recommended remediation measures to minimize risks.
- Drafted and maintained a wide range of documents, including policies, procedures, standards, and guides, to establish and maintain a robust cybersecurity posture.
- Participated actively in client meetings, effectively communicating cybersecurity risks, and advising on appropriate mitigation strategies to maintain business operations and safeguard sensitive data.

Assistant ICT Engineer | National Data Management Authority JANUARY 17TH 2022 – JANUARY 2023

- Utilized SIEM (Security Information and Event Management) software system to monitor and prioritize security events and incidents on the eGovernment Network Infrastructure to deter the risk of compromise to organizational ICT systems.
- Applied open-source intelligence skills to gather data on emerging threats to ICT infrastructure and systems used by the organization.
- Provided comprehensive threat reports throughout the period of proactive monitoring for the organization's departments while reporting the stages of remediation to ensure the safety of their information systems.

Freelance Engineer | Cenedex Software Solutions JULY 2020 – JULY 2021

- Maintained access to a collection of Linux operating systems to perform vulnerability scans and ensure software services were updated to deter possible compromise to web servers managed by the agency.
- Created comprehensive reports for management to communicate risks present on the assessed web servers as part of the lifecycle of securing the agencies' systems.



SKILLS

- Amazon Web Services Experienced with the EC2 service, Route 53, and AWS IAM services.
- LAMP Stack Linux, Apache, MySQL, and PHP
- HTML and CSS
- Linux Administration
- Vulnerability Assessments